<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elliot Lynde</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>elliotlynde.com</link>
    <atom:link href="elliotlynde.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
    
      }
        <item>
          <title>California's Hidden Gems</title>
          <description>&lt;h2 id='leaving_california'&gt;Leaving California&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fall, I&amp;#8217;ll be packing up and leaving California to move to New York. I had a great few years here filled with many fun weekend trips. If you love nature, California really is all that it&amp;#8217;s cracked up to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think back on some of the great places, I can remember several that not many people I know had visited. So, here&amp;#8217;s my parting gift to all you California weekend explorers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='paso_robles_central_coast'&gt;Paso Robles (Central Coast)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beautiful, laid-back wine country. Much more down-to-earth and affordable than Napa. Often, you can even meet and chat with the winemakers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paso Robles is starting to become well-known in the wine world for their high-quality reds (not many whites are made there) but the area hasn&amp;#8217;t become saturated with tourists like Napa and Sonoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The rolling hills of Paso Robles' src='/images/paso.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you check out one of my favorite restaurants: the taco stand outside &lt;a href='http://www.yelp.com/biz/la-reyna-market-paso-robles'&gt;La Reyna Mexican Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='channel_islands_near_santa_barbara'&gt;Channel Islands (Near Santa Barbara)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;What are those islands off the coast?&amp;#8221; - Melody while looking at a map of California&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, they&amp;#8217;re a National Park with an interesting history. Isolated from the mainland for thousands of years, the Channel Islands are often referred to as &amp;#8220;Galapagos Islands of North America.&amp;#8221; There are a couple of animals here that aren&amp;#8217;t found anywhere else in the world such as the Island Fox. In case you weren&amp;#8217;t aware, &lt;a href='https://www.facebook.com/MPKFOX'&gt;foxes are super cute.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Island Fox' src='/images/island_fox.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t miss the cave kayaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Cave Kayaking' src='/images/kayaking.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best parts about visiting the Channel Islands is the ferry ride out and back. You&amp;#8217;ll likely see Sea Lions and, if you get as lucky as we did, a Humpback Whale!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re into roughing it a bit, opt to camp overnight instead of taking the afternoon ferry back. Though the island we visited (Santa Cruz Island) is supposedly the most touristy of the Channel Islands, few seem to camp and so we were left with our own, semi-private island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='' src='/images/channel_islands.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='murphys_and_sonora_near_yosemite'&gt;Murphys and Sonora (near Yosemite)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a great area to escape and relax for a weekend. Great food, wine and some gold rush history including the historic route 49 and the world&amp;#8217;s largest gold nugget. Also stop by Calaveras Big Trees State Park to, well, see some big trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='A big tree' src='/images/big_trees.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='panther_beach_near_santa_cruz'&gt;Panther Beach (Near Santa Cruz)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 10 miles north of Santa Cruz lies the stunning Panther Beach. Though not exactly &amp;#8220;secret&amp;#8221; most haven&amp;#8217;t heard of it and knowledge of it is generally passed on by a friend who knows about it taking you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the time, take the Highway 1 down from San Francisco or Half Moon Bay and stop at some of the farm stands/shops for some fresh food. Also, check and see if &lt;a href='http://freewheelinfarm.com/'&gt;these folks&lt;/a&gt; are having a harvest party. Some dude selling dates at the Menlo Park Farmer&amp;#8217;s Market told us about it and we went on a whim. Ended up being an awesome time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Hiking down to Panther Beach' src='/images/panther.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='The beach' src='/images/panther2.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='onward'&gt;Onward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the tip of the iceberg. There are tons of cool places I never made it to and probably even more I didn&amp;#8217;t know existed. If you&amp;#8217;re lucky enough to live in California, make sure you spend some time exploring. You definitely won&amp;#8217;t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
          <link>elliotlynde.com/california-hidden-gems</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">elliotlynde.com/california-hidden-gems</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      }
        <item>
          <title>Traveling Ultralight</title>
          <description>&lt;h2 id='weighed_down'&gt;Weighed down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, a large part of the fun in international travel is the feeling of exploration in navigating my way around. Though this exploration can be fun, walking around a city for an hour trying to find a hostel with vacancy or the bus station that isn&amp;#8217;t on the map can get tiring and really put a damper on your trip, even with a good backpacking pack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Costa Rica 2008 (pre-ultralight and pre-UV water sterilizer):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='' src='/images/costa_rica_backpack.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='you_should_just_bring_a_backpack'&gt;&amp;#8220;You should just bring a backpack&amp;#8221;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trip to India was pretty last-minute. Basically, work asked if anyone wanted to go with about a week and a half notice. A couple of nights before I left, my team was out for dinner and they started asking me about the trip. I told them I always feel like I have too much stuff while traveling and that I wanted to pack lighter this time around. One of my coworkers said out of the blue &amp;#8220;you should just bring a backpack.&amp;#8221; I thought that was pretty crazy but he was insistent that it was a good idea so I gave it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='packing'&gt;Packing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped all assumptions and questioned every item I packed. It&amp;#8217;s easy to justify any item by asking &amp;#8220;would this come in handy?&amp;#8221; (most things could). The question to ask is &lt;strong&gt;what would happen if I forgot this?&lt;/strong&gt; and then only pack the items that you would be screwed without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I packed (not including the shirt, pants, boxers, socks I had on while taking the photo):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='' src='/images/india_backpack_contents.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='notable_inclusions'&gt;Notable inclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/ExOfficio-Mens-Give-N-Go-Boxer-Brief/dp/B001M0MN16'&gt;ExOfficio Give-N-Go boxers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lightweight, breathable underwear are simply amazing and a must-have for any ultralight traveller. Their Aegis® Microbe Shield™ allows you to wear them for days without washing them. Their slogan is actually &lt;a href='http://www.exofficio.com/products/details/mens-give-n-go-boxer'&gt;&amp;#8220;17 countries. 6 weeks. One pair of award-winning underwear. (Ok, maybe two.)&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;#8217;s stretching it a bit in my opinion. I washed them in a hotel sink every couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running shorts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pair of long-ish running shorts are really versatile. Other than using them for running, yoga, hiking or other exercise they can be used as a swimsuit since they are basically the same thing (shorts with a liner).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/MSR-PACKTOWLORIGINAL-Packtowl-Original/dp/B001QWGW6M'&gt;MSR Packtowel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small but incredibly absorbent towel that dries scary quick. Also, hotels or hostels often will lend you a towel. Using that is advantageous because you don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about packing it wet if you leave soon after using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/Smartwool-Outdoor-Light-Mini-Socks/dp/B008K7GX38/ref=sr_1_41?s=sporting-goods&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1357279705&amp;amp;sr=1-41'&gt;Smartwool Socks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, these are the only socks I wear. My feet feel cool in hot weather and warm in cold weather. You can wear them for days without them smelling bad. They are easy to wash in a hotel sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/SteriPen-SteriPEN-Adventurer-Opti/dp/B0095MOGEK/ref=pd_sbs_a_5'&gt;Steripen UV Water Purifier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drinking the tap water in India is inadvisable for foreigners. Not only are plastic bottles terrible for the environment (&lt;a href='http://www.treehugger.com/clean-technology/why-recycling-plastic-bottles-doesnt-help-the-problem-video.html'&gt;even when recycled&lt;/a&gt;), you also have to watch out for scams where bottled water is just tap water. I opt to just carry around this small UV light which allows me to fill up with tap water and sterilize it in 90 seconds. This is especially useful in remote areas where you might not have access to bottled water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.rei.com/product/784060/rei-adventures-pants-mens-32-inseam'&gt;REI Adventure Pants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lightweight, breathable and quick-drying. I brought two pairs so I could wear one while the other was airing out or drying after a wash. You really don&amp;#8217;t need more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.rei.com/product/794446/rei-sahara-tech-long-sleeve-shirt-mens'&gt;REI Sahara Shirt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same idea as the pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='noteable_exclusions'&gt;Noteable exclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/Lonely-Planet-India-Country-Travel/dp/1741797802'&gt;Lonely Planet India&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is 1,200 pages. Even the &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/Lonely-Planet-Kerala-Regional-Travel/dp/1741797810'&gt;South India &amp;amp; Kerala&lt;/a&gt; book (where I traveled mostly) is over 500. Though it was definitely worse for maps and just general browsing, I used the &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/India-Travel-Guide-Country-ebook/dp/B005GYGCOI/ref=tmm_kin_title_0'&gt;Kindle edition&lt;/a&gt;. It was worth the trade-off to save weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoes other than hiking boots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only wore hiking boots which was fine because the SmartWool socks helped me stay cool. Shoes are just too heavy and voluminous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raincoat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;#8217;t hit much rain. Plan was to just buy a cheap one if I needed it and then donate it. This is the perfect example of something that could easily be justified as useful but you wouldn&amp;#8217;t be screwed without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='freedom'&gt;Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myspace shot of the final result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='' src='/images/india_myspace.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling ultralight was quite a liberating experience. Whether I was running to catch a bus or making an impromptu beach trip, being able to easily carry everything on my back helped me have a trip that was simultaneously more adventurous and less stressful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
          <link>elliotlynde.com/traveling-ultralight</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">elliotlynde.com/traveling-ultralight</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      }
        <item>
          <title>Energy Experiment</title>
          <description>&lt;h2 id='why_measure_my_energy'&gt;Why measure my energy?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it hard to accomplish almost anything outside of work. It&amp;#8217;s easy to say &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t have time&amp;#8221; but really, even if I work long hours, it shouldn&amp;#8217;t be hard to find at least an hour every day to write, code on a side project, learn a language, etc. Even if I worked 10 hours every day (I try to work fewer than that), commuted two, worked out one and slept eight, I&amp;#8217;d still have three hours left over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really think that the limiting factor is energy, not time. After a long day of work, I don&amp;#8217;t have the energy to work on something else. Even during the workday, my energy seems to fluctuate. Sometimes I&amp;#8217;m on fire. Sometimes my brain feels like mush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seeing someone mention a &lt;a href='http://madhadron.com/?p=254'&gt;similar experiment on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; I was curious to see if my fluctuations in energy were predictable. If I understood them well, I could at least plan my day better around them if not smooth out my energy to avoid crashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='how_i_did_it'&gt;How I did it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To measure my energy, I made a &lt;a href='https://github.com/elynde/energy'&gt;simple Android app&lt;/a&gt; that would pop up every hour, vibrate and ask me what my energy level was. To keep things simple, I just did three levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='' src='/images/log.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I would have a system for passively measuring my energy level to eliminate any bias I might add but I couldn&amp;#8217;t think of anything feasible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='what_i_learned'&gt;What I learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t allow myself to look at the graphs while I ran the experiment to avoid bias. After the month, here is what I saw:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src='/images/results.png' class='max_width_100_percent' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? I think there are a few things: &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I tend to crash after lunch and in the evening after work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really good to know. To smooth-out the after lunch crash, I might try to nap more often or workout then. In the least, eating a smaller lunch might help smooth out that crash. To preempt the after-work crash, I could spend my commute (on a shuttle) relaxing so I feel recharged when I get home. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a night owl.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually thought I wasn&amp;#8217;t too much of a night owl anymore but this experiment says otherwise. As you can see in the graph, my energy levels are pretty high at night. Maybe I&amp;#8217;ll experiment with trying to change this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
          <link>elliotlynde.com/energy-experiment</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">elliotlynde.com/energy-experiment</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
